♪♪～
25th Night
Alibaba and Aladdin
（白龍）一体　何が…。
（アラジン）くっ！
What happened to him?
He was taken in by all of the dark intentions.
黒い意志に
飲み込まれてしまったんだ。
（アリババ）お前も来るんだ　アラジン。
You will be too, Aladdin.
くっ！
ソロモンの知恵！
Wisdom of Solmon!
うわっ！
アラジン殿！
Mister Aladdin!
It's no good. The band on his forehead is blocking me!
ダメだ…　あの額の飾りに→
邪魔をされてしまう。
Then all I need to do is destroy that, right?
≪（モルジアナ）
なら　あれを壊せばよいのですね？
Morg!
モルさん！
（白龍）モルジアナ殿。　どうして…。
Miss Morgiana, why aren't you resting?
A little of my magoi has returned.
少しですが　魔力が回復しました。
It's not like you to be deceived by an illusion, Alibaba!
そんな　まやかしに
とらわれるなんて→
アリババさんらしくありません！
ドン！
力ずくでも→
I will make you remember who you
used to be, even if I have to use force!
いつものあなたに戻してみせます。
♪♪～
It's spread all the way over here already?
（ヤムライハ）
もう　こんな所にまで…。　あっ！
Well look at you, getting cocky and taking your eyes off the battle.
（アポロニウス）よそ見とは　余裕よのう。
くっ！
You used the mist to weaken the light?
（アポロニウス）霧で　光を弱めたか。
Good, but once you're out of magoi, you won't be able to use such tricks!
しかし　魔力が尽きれば
それも　できなくなろう。
くっ…。
（アポロニウス）ひょっひょっひょっ！
ドスッ！
グワァー！
W-What is that stuff?
な…　なんだ？　これは。
≫（兵士）ひぃ～！
（一同）あっ！
うわぁ…。
It's oozing up this way!
上がってくるぞ！
≪（ドラコーン）どけ！
Out of the way!
♪♪～
（ドラコーン）くっ！　まずいな。→
This is bad.
All troops are to retreat to the inside of the barrier!
全軍　結界の内側まで下がれ！
Damn.
（シンドバッド）くっ…。
（ジャーファル）シン。
Sin.
Their real aim is Alibaba and Aladdin.
（シンドバッド）ヤツらの本当の狙いは
アリババ君とアラジンだ。
こちらは陽動だったということか。
This is just a diversion.
That can't...
そんな…。
（シンドバッド）こうなった以上　俺が…。
If this gets any worse, I will have to...
But-!
（ジャーファル）しかし…。
（紅玉）シンドバッド様！
King Sinbad!
（２人）あっ。
（ジャーファル）紅玉姫。
Princess Kougyoku?
（紅玉）わ…　私に…
私に　お手伝いさせてください。
Please... Please allow me to help!
What?
えっ？
はあ～！
ドカッ！
くっ…　ふっ！
あっ。
ガキン！
くっ！
Stop this.
もう　やめるんだ。
I will not.
嫌です。
あなたを元に戻すまで諦めません。
I will not give up until I remind you of who you were!
（イスナーン）ちっ！
あっ。　ううっ！
ドーン！
モルジアナ殿！
Miss Morgiana!
（２人）あっ。
くっ…　くそ！
Dammit!
（白龍・心の声）≪何も
できないなんて　俺は…　俺は！≫
I can't afford to be useless right now! I...
I...
くっ！
Zagan! Lend me your power!
（白龍）
ザガン！　俺に　力を貸してくれ！
♪♪～
（ザガン）ふっ！　ようやく呼んだか。→
Well, it's about time you called for me.
意地を張るねぇ　君は。→
You're so stubborn.
Not like that's a bad thing.
でも嫌いじゃないよ　そういうの。
Zagan, why are you here?
ザガンくん　どうして…。
ふん。→
ちょっと物足りないですが
彼に　賭けることにしたんです→
He's not perfect, but I decided to bet on him, Magi.
マギよ。
（白龍）んん！　これなら！
This is it!
The rest is up to you, crybaby.
あとは君しだいだよ　泣き虫君。
はあ～！
ぐっ！
ドカッ！
♪♪～
くっ…　あっ！
Prince Hakuryuu.
白龍さん。
俺が　隙を作ります。
I will create an opening.
あっ。
（白龍）いけますか？
Can you do it?
ふっ　もちろんです。
Of course.
♪♪～
はあ～～！
ガキン！
♪♪～
あっ！
Miss Morgiana!
（白龍）モルジアナ殿！
ドカッ！
パリン！
（アリババ　イスナーン）ぐわぁ～！
Aladdin!
アラジン！
ソロモンの知恵！
Wisdom of Solomon!
（アリババ　イスナーン）うわぁ～～!!
Alibaba...
≪アリババくん≫
♪♪～
あっ。
魔力が尽きたようだのう。
It looks like you're out of magoi.
ひょっひょっひょっひょっ！
ううっ！
パキン！
きゃあ～！
（ヤムライハ）ううっ！
Ha! Well don't you look great!
ひょ～ひょっひょっひょっ！
いいざまじゃ！→
所詮　魔導師など
我ら金属器使いの→
Even you magicians aren't a match for us metal vessel wielders!
敵ではないのだ。
ひょっひょっひょっひょっ！
（ヤムライハ）下衆じじい。
ひょっ？
Hey pervert.
What?
You sure do talk a lot.
御託が多いわよ。
What was that saying? Oh yes. The
weaker the dog, the louder it howls.
ああ～
弱い犬ほど　よくほえるってやつね。
お…　おにょれ～！
Wh-Why you!
I'll crush you with my Djinn Equip!
わしの全身魔装を　見るがいい～！
♪♪～
Extreme Magic: Flash Al-Alaf!
極大魔法→
「焼夷光葬砲」！→
死ね～！
Die!
♪♪～
Unbelievable! You were able to reflect back my extreme magic attack?
バカな！　わしの極大魔法を
はね返すとは…。→
H-How?
な…　なぜじゃ～!?
お主の魔力は　もう…。
I'm out... of magoi!
さっき　あなたが砕いたのは→
What you shattered earlier were some magical tools I invented.
私が発明した魔法道具なの。→
世界で唯一の魔力蓄蔵装置。
They were actually the only magoi
storage devices in the whole world.
No! You're nothing but a little magician!
そんな！
ただの魔導師ごときが…。
ごめんね。　私　天才魔導師なの。
Sorry, that's genius little magician to you.
お…　おにょれ～！　貴様…→
Curse you!
貴様ぁ～～!!
Curse you!!
ドスッ！
ううっ！→
ああ～…。
A metal vessel user who's out of
magoi is nothing but a sitting duck.
（スパルトス）
魔力が尽きた金属器使いなど→
もはや　ただの的です。
（ヒナホホ）うおぉ～～りゃ～！
♪♪～
It's working, but we're out of luck unless we can
destroy it in one hit like Yamu did with her magic.
（ピスティ）
効いてるけど　ヤムの魔法くらい→
一気にやらないと…。　あっ。
（２人）ん？
（マスルール）あれは…。
That's...
The princess from Kou?!
（シャルルカン）煌帝国の姫さんか？
（紅玉）悲哀と隔絶の精霊よ
汝が王に　力を集わせ→
Spirit of sorrow and solitude,
join thy power with the power thy king.
地上を裁く　大いなる激流を
もたらさんことを！
Bring forth the raging rapids of judgment on this earth!
♪♪～
「水神召海」！
Vaniel Ganezza!
♪♪～
Is this also according to your calculations, Sin?
これも　あなたの
読みどおりなのですか？→
シン。
（シンドバッド）まだ終わっていない。→
It's not over yet.
Prepare to cast transportation magic.
転送魔法の用意を。
アリババくん　どこだい？
Alibaba, where are you?
あっ。
アリババ…　くん？
Ali...baba?
あっ！
あっ。
帰ろう　アリババくん。
Let's go back, Alibaba.
Everyone's waiting for you.
みんな　待ってるよ。
なあ…。
ん？
Hey.
どうして
俺たちは　生きるんだろう？
Why are we alive?
If everything's already fated, why do we have to chase that fate?
すべてが　運命で決まってるなら→
どうして　その決まってる運命を
たどらなくちゃいけないんだ？
I've made so many mistakes.
俺は　何べんも間違ってきた。
If making those mistakes was my fate, I...
間違うことすら
運命だっていうのなら→
俺は　もう…。
Is that really how you feel in your heart?
それは　本当に君の心の言葉かい？
アリババくん→
Alibaba, fate is not a path set in stone.
運命は
言いなりになるものじゃない。
乗り越えることで　命を…
世界を　前へ進めるものなんだよ。
It is something that moves you, and the whole world, forward when you reach and surpass it.
After I met you, we surpassed many fates.
君と出会って　僕らは
いくつもの運命を越えてきた。
We had our hard times, and saw our share of sad things.
つらいこともあったよ。
悲しいことも。
But you always got back up.
でも
君は　いつでも立ち上がってきた。
前に進むことを　諦めなかった。
You never stopped trying to move forward.
That's right. You're a hero.
そう。　君は　勇気ある人。
I can tell.
僕は知ってる。
気付いているかい？
Did you notice?
The people you encouraged with your strong faith and conviction...
君が
その信念で　勇気づけた人たちは→
They are all standing up, looking forward, and facing their futures.
みんな　前を向いて
それぞれの道に　立ち向かう。
Your courage has become a power to move the world forward.
君の勇気が
世界を動かす力になっているんだ。
Your struggle guides the rukh.
君の戦いこそが　ルフの導き。
In other words, your fate!
運命そのものなんだよ。
♪♪～
If you made a mistake, just search for an even better answer.
間違えたなら
探せばいいんだよ　よりよい道を。
I'm sure there's one out there.
それは　きっとある。
きっと　君なら見つけられる。
And I'm sure you're the one who can find it.
After all, you're my favorite person, Alibaba!
だって　君は　僕の大好きな
アリババくんだからね！
アラジン…。
Aladdin...
♪♪～
Alibaba!
アリババさん！
あっ！
♪♪～
（２人）ふふっ。　ん？
In front of us lies true darkness.
この先に　本当の闇がある。
Let's go, Alibaba!
行こう　アリババくん。
ああ。
Right!
（イスナーン）シンドバッドめ
煌の姫まで手なずけていたとは。→
That damn Sinbad. He even has that Kou princess eating out of his hand.
But the curse on him is still strong.
だが　ヤツへの呪いは健在。
And King Alibaba is my slave.
アリババ王は　もはや　私の奴隷だ。
Perhaps I should call it a day-
これで　よしとするか。　ん？
あっ！
（シンドバッド）やあ。
Yo!
You tried to start a war with my country. Did you really think you could leave with your life?
俺の国に　戦争を仕掛けておいて→
生きて帰れると思ったのか？
くっ！
（シンドバッド）支配と服従の精霊→
Spirit of control and obedience, Focalor.
フォカロル…。
あっ。
Live in my frame.
我が身に宿れ。
ははっ！　バカめ。→
Fool.
呪いを受けたまま
魔装などすれば→
If you perform a Djinn Equip under that curse,
お前を　むしばむ力も
強くなるだけだ！
all you'll do is strengthen the power that's eating away at your insides!
うっ！　うぅ…。
（イスナーン）ちょうどよい。
Perfect.
You shall also join our Father!
貴様も
我らが父のもとに下るがいい！
くっ…　んん！
は～ははははっ！　おおっ？
♪♪～
なんだ？　あれは…。　あっ。
What is that?
♪♪～
ふっ。
く…　黒ルフを…。　あっ。
T-The black rukh are-!
Unfortunately, my body's already been cursed.
（シンドバッド）
あいにく　すでに呪われた身でね。
Your curse wasn't strong enough to stick.
お前の呪いは
取るに足らなかったな。
あっ！　まさか…。
Don't tell me you're-!
♪♪～
必死で　ザガンに行ってくれた
アリババ君に悪いからな。
I feel bad for Alibaba. He rushed so desperately into Zagan for me.
この力は　最後まで→
That's why I didn't plan on using this power unless I absolutely had to.
使わないつもりだったんだが…。
半分　堕転して…。
You're already fallen halfway from grace?!
「風裂斬」！
Foraz Zora!
ドオォーーン！
うわぁ～～あぁ～!!
バキン！
♪♪～
この世界の未来に
お前たちは　必要ない。
This world doesn't need Al-Tharmen in its future.
（２人）はぁ　はぁ　はぁ…。
あっ。
♪♪～
あっ！
はっ。
やあ　君だね？
Hey. It's you, isn't it?
（イスナーン）ああ。
Yeah.
Can you get out of Alibaba?
アリババくんから
出ていってくれるかい？
If that's what you wish, then all Alibaba needs to stab me with that sword.
そう望むなら
アリババ王　その剣で　俺を突け。
くっ…。
（イスナーン）さっきまでとは違うさ。→
It's different now.
My real body was just destroyed by Sinbad.
俺の本体は
シンドバッドに　ほふられた。→
もはや
俺は　単なる　呪いの核にすぎん。
I'm simply the nucleus of the curse now.
はぁ…　やれよ。
Do it.
♪♪～
Before that, I ask you.
その前に　君たちに尋ねる。
ん？
Why have you made this world your enemy?
なぜ　この世界に　仇をなす？
（イスナーン）貴様　やはり
ソロモンの代行者なのだな。
I knew it. You represent Solomon.
When the group of you act, war and poverty are born.
君たちが動くことで
世界に　戦争や貧困が生まれる。
なぜ　そんなことをするのか→
I, myself and no one else, want to know why.
ほかの誰でもなく
僕自身が聞きたい。
In order to create darkness on this world.
この世界に　暗黒を作るためさ。
And in order to set everything free,
そして　すべてを解放する。
この世界を支配する監獄…→
from the prison that binds this world.
In other words, from fate.
すなわち　運命からだ。
（イスナーン）誰かに決められた
結末へ向けて敷かれた→
From an already determined ending, from an imposed path that cannot be changed.
あらがえぬ道。　そこから逃れ→
The only way to escape from that and live freely...
生きられる唯一の術…。
is by falling from grace.
（イスナーン）それが　堕転だ。
You are misunderstanding fate.
君たちは　運命を誤解している。
If you deny fate, then the world loses the power to
move forward and will have no choice but to perish.
運命を否定すれば
世界は　前へ進む力を失い→
滅びるしかなくなるんだ
「理想郷」のように。
Like Alma Toran did.
「理想郷」か。
Like Alma Toran, huh?
（一同・回想）((わあ～～！))
Presenting our great King Solomon and his household, the three Magi!
（代表）((我らが偉大なる
ソロモン王と　眷属たち→
三人のマギたちよ！))
Paimon, Zagan, we must be more diligent for the sake of our king!
（アモン）((王のために
更に精進するのじゃぞ→
パイモン　ザガン))
（ザガン）((うるせぇ　くそじじい))
Be quiet, old man.
My King.
((王よ))
Our chosen one, the great King.
((我らが選びし　大王よ))
♪♪～
((ドォーン！))
（イスナーン）あの時代より　我々は→
Even back in those days, we had this same argument over and over again.
何億と　同じ議論を繰り返し→
In the end, we all met our ends. Together.
その果てに滅ぼし合ったのだ　共に。
((ドォーン！))
♪♪～
Even in this world, there is no way for the two of us to understand each other.
この世界でも
お前たちと分かり合うことはない。
Come, get rid of me.
さあ　俺を消せよ。
さもなくば　お前たちを巻き込んで
自滅するぞ！
If you don't, I'll drag the two of you down with me in death!
ガキン！
アリババくんが　その剣を使えば→
If Alibaba uses that sword, he can banish you for eternity.
彼を永遠に
消滅させることもできるよ。
Then do it. If you are not prepared to deal with what lies ahead,
やれよ。
清濁併せ持つ覚悟がなければ→
この先も　貴様は　苦しみ続ける。
your road ahead will continue to be filled with suffering.
That man will not win.
あの男には　絶対　勝てん。
ううっ！
ガン！
Why did you not kill me?
なぜ殺さない？
俺は　もう憎みたくないんだ。
I don't want to hate anymore.
I don't know if I can do it!
できるかなんて分かんねぇ。
でも　もし　俺にしかできない→
But if there's something that only I can do,
運命の戦いがあるなら→
if I can fight battles to guide my fate,
これが　今
俺ができる　精いっぱいの答えだ。
then this is the best answer I can give right now!
♪♪～
Alibaba.
アリババくん。
♪♪～
How humiliating.
（イスナーン）屈辱だよ。
こんなに穏やかな気持ちで→
I'm being sent back to Solomon with such a peaceful feeling in my heart.
ソロモンのもとへ還されようとは。
もう二度と
顔向けできまいと思っていたのに。
I thought I would never be able to face him again.
♪♪～
Isaac.
（ドゥニヤ）イサアク…。
イサアク。
Isaac!
♪♪～
あっ。
よかったね。
I'm so glad.
もう大丈夫だよ。
Everything's okay now.
♪♪～
You made up a little part of Alibaba.
君は　アリババくんの中に
少し混じっていたんだね。
You held back the curse for him, didn't you?
呪いも　抑えていてくれたんだろ？
ありがとう。
Thank you.
♪♪～
アリババさん。
（白龍）アリババ殿。
Alibaba!
Mister Alibaba.
うっ…　みんな。
You guys...
Welcome back, Alibaba.
おかえり　アリババくん。
心配かけたな。
Sorry for worrying you all.
でも　おかげで
ばっちり元に戻ったぜ。
But I'm 100% back now!
本当に　大丈夫なんですね？
ああ。
So you're okay now?
Yeah.
よかった…。
I'm so glad...
あっ！　モルジアナ。
Morgiana!
（白龍）モルジアナ殿。
大丈夫。　眠ったみたいだよ。
Miss Morgiana.
It's okay. I think she's just sleeping.
You were fantastic, Morg.
頑張ったもんね　モルさん。
ありがとな。
んん…。
Thanks.
お前もな　白龍。
あっ。
Thanks to you too, Hakuryuu.
You were able to conquer Zagan.
ザガン　手に入れたんだな。
よかったぜ。
Nicely done!
あっ…　はい。
Thank you.
（アラジン　アリババ）ふふっ。
Let's go back!
さあ　僕たちも帰ろう。
ああ。
Yeah.
♪♪～
なあ　アラジン。
Hey, Aladdin.
How do I say this...
なんつぅか　その…→
いろいろあり過ぎて
あれだけど…。
Stuff kinda went overboard and got a little weird, but...
Thanks for everything, okay?
とにかく　全部ありがとな。
Thanks to you too!
僕の方こそだよ。
あっ。
I'm so happy to have met you and become friends with you.
君に会えて　君と友達になれて→
本当によかった。
ははっ。
We've come a long way since Qishan, haven't we?
チーシャンで出会ってから→
随分　遠くまで来たよな。
うん。
Yeah.
I wonder how long the two of us can keep this up?
どこまで行けるかな？　俺たち。
♪♪～
Forever.
ずっとさ。
♪♪～
I'm sure our adventures will continue forever, and take us to places far, far away.
きっと　ずっと遠い未来→
はるかな場所まで
僕らの冒険は続く。
ああ。
Yeah!
♪♪～
On that journey, the backwards flow of fate will always target you and block your way.
その旅路の中で　運命の逆流は→
常に　君を目がけ　立ちはだかる。
♪♪～
でも　それを乗り越えて→
But you will surpass it and one day become king.
いつか　君は王になるだろう。
You will become a leader who will guide this world forward.
世界を前へと導く　先導者になる。
♪♪～
I'm a Magi.
僕は　マギ。
I've come to lead you to that path.
そんな君を
導くために　やってきたんだから。
♪♪～
ルフに愛された者たちが動きだす。
Those loved by the rukh start their journeys.
♪♪～
miwatasu kagiri no kouya ni hitori tatteirunda
In the wilderness, as far as the eye can see, stands a lone figure
sorya miburui mo surun darou
Surely he trembles as he stands
Good job, everyone.
みんな
ご苦労だった。→
One danger has passed, but in front of us still lie many difficulties.
一つの
危機は去ったが　俺たちの前には→
osanai shoujo ga yume ni miteiru hakuba no ouji mitaina mono
A young girl dreams of a prince on a white horse
まだ
多くの困難が　待ち受けている。→
But do not fear.
だが恐れるな。→
We have much strength by our sides.
今　力は
俺たちのもとに
集いつつある。
bokura mo dokka de shiranai uchi ni kitai shiteshimatteitano kamo
Unwittingly, we also fall to such dreams of perfection
We'll reach out and grab the world we've been dreaming of
つかんで
みせるぞ
この手で。
with our own two hands!
俺たちが
願い続けてきた
世界を。
fukanzen na kono sekai wo dareka ga
No one will recreate
Yessir!
（一同）はっ！
それこそが　俺たちの運命なのだ。
That's our fate!
kakitashite kureru nante nai
this imperfect world for us
世界を求める人々の旅が
加速してゆく。
The roads traveled by those who desire to rule this world are getting shorter.
shinjiru toiu kotoba wo kimi ha kodomoppoi to warau kai?
Will you call me naïve if I say that I still dream?
I see.
そうか。
（ジュダル）ああ。→
Yeah. Told you Sindria would shrug off those fossils.
miwatasu kagiri no kouya de yukisaki wo shimesu mono
In the wilderness, as far as the eye can see, shines a guiding light
やっぱり　おやじたちくらいじゃ
びくともしなかったみたいだぜ→
シンドリアは。
それでこそだ　シンドバッド。
But that's Sinbad.
mune ni daite aruitekou sekai ga hohoemu
Hold it close as you go and the world will smile upon you
I'm looking forward to crossing swords with him.
刃を交えるのが楽しみだ。→
kono basho ga doko darou to miagereba mabataku hoshi
If you're lost, consult the twinkling stars
皆も心せよ。　世界のすべては→
Listen well!
Everything in this world will belong to our empire!
我が帝国が　手に入れる。
♪♪～
sono shita de kimi wo omoeba warukunai yoru ni naru
If I think of you while gazing at those stars, the night brightens
tsumetai mune ni hi ga tomoru
and a warm fire lights in my heart
For Magi to appear means that we have reached a turning point in history.
歴史の節目に　マギは現る。
What direction will this world head in?
世界は　どこに
行こうとしてるんだろうね？
今日正午過ぎ、
大阪府東大阪市の住宅で火事があ
り
住人と見られる女性１人が死亡し
家族４人がケガをした。
今日正午過ぎ、東大阪市上六万寺
町の
玉置政敬さんの家から、